The adoption of unfair means in the examination means copying in the examination. It does not simply mean copying from books etc. Inside the hall, it includes any sort of malpractice [দুর্নীতি] in or outside the hall to succeed in the examination. It is one of the signs of degenerating [নিম্নগামী] conditions existing [বিদ্যমান] in our society. Many students without preparing lessons waste their valuable time in gossiping, roaming, playing, travelling etc. As a result, they are compelled [বাধ্য] to adopt unfair means in the hall. By adopting unfair means a student frustrates [বিফল করা] the very purpose [উদ্দেশ্য] of the examination. Merely [শুধু] committing to memory [মুখস্থ করা] and vomiting it in the examination halls cannot determine [নির্ধারণ] the merit [মেধা] of a student. In order to solve copying in the examination the govt. has taken some preventive [প্রতিরোধী] measures. First of all the govt. is trying to raise [উত্থিত] public awareness [সচেতনতা] through mass media. Recently, the government has enforced [আরোপ] a law that if any student is found copying in the examination hall, she/he will be expelled from the examination hall. If any invigilator is found helping any examinee [পরীক্ষার্থী], legal action will be taken against her/him. Even if outsiders are found involved [জড়িত] in helping any examinee in copying, they will also be punished. The government has interchanged [অদলবদল করা] the examination centres and formed [গঠন] invigilation [পরিদর্শক] teams to monitor the overall condition of the examination centre. The very system of education should be changed. Above all, the government, the teachers, the guardians, the students, the intellectuals [বুদ্ধিজীবী], the politicians and all the conscious [সচেতন] sections of the country should come forward to tackle [সম্মুখীন হত্তয়া] the problem.
